Madhav Malhotra

Designer, Developer, Writer, Analyst

I am a 17-year-old high school student living in Toronto, Canada. I'm very passionate about digital technologies, especially in artificial intelligence, data analysis, and web development. To put these skills to use, I've worked on projects to help companies with real-world issues such as optimising retail costs, decreasing barriers to energy access, and scaling in developing countries. In addition, I've worked on many personal projects and hackathons to research opportunities in major societal challenges. I am open to internships or part-time opportunities focused on digital design, research/consulting, or development.

Contact Information

madhav.malhotra003@gmail.com

madhavmalhotra.com

in madhav-malhotra

Madhav-Malhotra

@MadhavMalhotra_

@madhav-malhotraoo3



Experience

The Knowledge Archives

Cofounder and Editor (2020.07 - present)

Editing and distributing a podcast interviewing researchers at the forefront of STEM disciplines. Designing cover art, logos, video graphics, and other digital media. Cold-emailing, tracking outreach campaigns, and recording interviews.

The Plastic Shift

.....

Cofounder and Developer (2020.03 - present)

Designing, optimising, and maintaining a website to showcase research on the root causes of plastic pollution. Writing articles, editing podcasts, and designing infographics to share plastic pollution research. Cold-emailing, tracking outreach campaigns, and automating social media presence. Establishing collaborations to create webinars, online courses, and other content with companies in the industry.

......

The Knowledge Society

.....

Activator (2018.09 - 2020.09)

Consulted on recommendations to help companies like Walmart, Wealthsimple, Kidogo, and Sidewalk Labs to scale. Created Excel dashboards for team tracking, created case studies for training workshops, and mentored students. Researched machine learning models and data analysis with Python and Excel. Created articles, infographics, reports, and mockups showcasing research on societal problems like energy poverty.

Prohibio Health

Cofounder and Developer (2019.05 - 2019.09)

Placed top 25 in Microsoft's Discover Al Challenge while developing data models on insect disease transmission. Joined the DMZ Sandbox accelerator to learn about startup strategy and placed top 5 in their pitch competition. Won the ElevateMoonshot contest for youth's entrepreneurial ideas at Canada's largest technology conference.



Projects

Please visit my website (madhavmalhotra.com) for my full portfolio.

Kidogo Early Years

Kidogo is a startup bringing certified early childhood education to East Africa. I created a recommendation for them outlining how to use e-commerce sales and cross-subsidies to fund this growth, but COVID-19 stopped the plans.

Plastic Bank

Plastic Bank is a startup that builds recycling infrastructure in developing countries. I worked with their team to launch an online course to attract new volunteers and engage employees at partner corporations.

.



Skills

Technology

•••••

.....

......

Proficient: React, js, HTML, CSS, Microsoft Excel, Photoshop, Google Suite, Audacity. Knowledgeable: Figma, Davinci Resolve. Node, js, Hootsuite, Notion.

Soft Skills

Proficient: Public Speaking, Leadership, Mentorship, Research, Root-Cause Analysis Knowledgeable: Networking & Outreach, Team Management.

Other

Proficient: Writing, Digital Design, English, Hindi. Knowledgeable: Video-Editing, Photography, French.



Education

St. Robert CHS / Cameron Heights CI

International Baccalaureate & Ontario Secondary School Diploma (2017.09 - present)

Leader of Recycling Program, Tour Guide at Anne Frank Exhibition, Audiovisual Technician at Tech Crew, Youth Writer at the Kitchener Public Library, Math Club, Music Council, Environmental Council, French Club, Key Club, Senior Concert Band, Jazz Band, Choir.